{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Some types of variation are due to changes in the genetic material. What is this type of change called?", "opta": "Fertilisation", "optb": "Mutation", "optc": "Radiation", "optd": "Sterilisation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the process of choosing parent organisms for the characteristics that is wanted in their offspring?", "opta": "Active selection", "optb": "Reproductive selection", "optc": "Selective breeding", "optd": "Breeding selection", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which protein has been produced generating a transgenic sheep that is used for replacement therapy for individuals at risk from emphysema?", "opta": "Plasminogen activator (tPA)", "optb": "\u03b1-anti trypsin (AAT)", "optc": "Casein", "optd": "Amyloid precursor proteins", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the word used to describe what happens when the nucleus of a sperm joins with the nucleus of an egg cell?", "opta": "Sex", "optb": "Fertilisation", "optc": "Intercourse", "optd": "Reproduction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA into fish is injected into", "opta": "pronuclei", "optb": "cytoplasm", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transgenic goats have been used to produce which of the following protein that is used for dissolving blood clots?", "opta": "Amyloid precursor protein", "optb": "\u03b11-anti trypsin (AAT)", "optc": "Casein", "optd": "A variant of human tissue-type plasminogen activator", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transfection refers to which of the following?", "opta": "Synthesis of mRNA from DNA template", "optb": "Synthesis of protein based on mRNA sequence", "optc": "Introduction of foreign gene in to a cell", "optd": "The process by which a cell become malignant", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chromosomes may be isolated from metaphase cells by", "opta": "hypertonic lysis", "optb": "hypotonic lysis", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "isotonic lysis", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Superovulation is primarily the result of", "opta": "decreased atresia in medium and large follicles (>1.7 mm)", "optb": "increased atresia in medium and large follicles (>1.7 mm)", "optc": "increased atresia in the large follicles (<1.7 mm)", "optd": "decreased atresia in small follicles (<1.7 mm)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Genetic change can occur only in", "opta": "one way", "optb": "two ways", "optc": "three ways", "optd": "four ways", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these carries the thousands of genes needed to allow animal and plant cells to pass on inherited characteristics?", "opta": "Chromosomes", "optb": "Chromatogram", "optc": "Chromatography", "optd": "Chromium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Animal pharming can be defined as", "opta": "growing animals for farming", "optb": "programming animals to produce novel products", "optc": "generating transgenic animals for farming", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a fertilized egg cell develops into an embryo, the entropy of the living system", "opta": "decreases", "optb": "increases", "optc": "remains constant", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the transfer of whole individual chromosomes, they are isolated from the cells at", "opta": "prophase", "optb": "metaphase", "optc": "telophase", "optd": "anaphase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Fusion of karyoplast with the enucleated cell is achieved in presence of", "opta": "cytochalasin B", "optb": "polyethylene glycol", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "alcohol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements best describes a clone?", "opta": "An artificial life form", "optb": "An offspring where all of the genetic material in every cell is identical to that of both parents", "optc": "An offspring where all of the genetic material in every cell is identical to that of one of its parents", "optd": "A type of sheep", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In transgenic fish, the genes are introduced by", "opta": "microinjection in fish", "optb": "viruses", "optc": "transfer of whole nuclei", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Production of transgenic animals require transfections of", "opta": "eggs or embryos", "optb": "stem cells", "optc": "red blood cells", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Variation is caused by genes", "optb": "Variation is caused by the environment", "optc": "Variation can be caused by both genes and the environment", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following gene have been introduced into the transgenic fish?", "opta": "Human or rat gene for growth hormone", "optb": "Chicken gene for delta crystalline protein", "optc": "E. coli gene for \u03b2-galactosidase", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cloning is a method by which numbers of genetically identical organisms are derived from a single organism by", "opta": "vegetative propagation", "optb": "vegetative initiation", "optc": "vegetative termination", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are the method of transfection for making transgenic animals?", "opta": "Transfer of whole nuclei", "optb": "Transfer of whole individual chromosomes or fragment", "optc": "Transfer of DNA", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA microinjection into the egg has been used to produce which of the following transgenic animals?", "opta": "Mice", "optb": "Chicken", "optc": "Pigs", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transgenic goats produce a variant of human tissue type plasminogen activator protein in", "opta": "blood", "optb": "urine", "optc": "milk", "optd": "muscles", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the rapid genetic progress, embryo transfer (ET)", "opta": "will be as potent a tool as AI (artificial insemination)", "optb": "will not be as potent a tool as AI (artificial insemination)", "optc": "ET can't be used at all", "optd": "will be a superior tool than AI", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Enucleation of the cells can be achieved by treating the cells with", "opta": "polyethylene glycol", "optb": "cytochalasin B", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "alcohol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When the cells are enucleated and centrifuged, nuclei", "opta": "detach from cell and settle at the bottom", "optb": "detach from cell and remain in the supernatant", "optc": "nuclei remain attached to the cell", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Superovulation is an", "opta": "increased ovulatory response by external hormonal therapy", "optb": "decreased ovulatory response by external hormonal therapy", "optc": "decreased ovulatory response by internal hormonal therapy", "optd": "increased ovulatory response by internal hormonal therapy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following best describes artificial insemination?", "opta": "Transplanting an embryo into the uterus", "optb": "Fertilization of an egg in a test tube", "optc": "Selectively breeding healthy animals", "optd": "Taking the sperm and placing it directly", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which part of a cell carries the information that is passed from one generation to the next?", "opta": "Cell", "optb": "Nucleus", "optc": "Cytoplasm", "optd": "Chloroplast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA is microinfected into the fertilized egg", "opta": "after the fusion of male and female nuclei", "optb": "before the fusion of male and female nuclei", "optc": "at the time of fusion of male and female nuclei", "optd": "any time, it can be infected", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In which year, Dolly the first mammalian clone was born?", "opta": "1995", "optb": "1997", "optc": "1996", "optd": "1998", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is false?", "opta": "Continuous variation produces a spread of variation within a population", "optb": "Discontinuous variation is the result of genetics alone", "optc": "Blood group is an example of discontinuous variation", "optd": "Discontinuous variation is influenced by the environment", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Embryo transfer (ET) refers to the technique by which fertilized ova are collected from the reproductive tract of a genetically", "opta": "superior female and transferred to the inferior", "optb": "inferior female and transferred to the superior", "optc": "balanced female", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The number of follicles at any particular stage is governed by", "opta": "the rate of entry of dormant follicles", "optb": "the rate of growth of follicles", "optc": "the rate of loss of follicles", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The nucleous of mature unfertilized ovum may be removed by", "opta": "irradiation", "optb": "surgery", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "neutralization and homogenization", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Karyoplast is", "opta": "cells devoid of cell wall", "optb": "nuclei", "optc": "nuclei with only some residual plasma membrane", "optd": "cell with nucleus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The success of embryo transplantation depends upon the ability to obtain an increased number of embryos from animals of superior genetic merit, which can be achieved by the use of", "opta": "exogenous gonadatrophic hormones", "optb": "endogenous gonadatrophic hormones", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "FSH (Follicle Stimulating Hormone)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Multiple ovulation and embryo transfer (MOET)", "opta": "can increase the rate of progress in dairy cattle", "optb": "allows progeny testing of males", "optc": "allows progeny testing of females", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The technique, mainly used for the diagnosing birth defects in the fetus by means of needle, is called", "opta": "amniocentesis", "optb": "ectogensis", "optc": "transplantation", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of these established cell lines originate from a mouse embryo?", "opta": "3T3", "optb": "BHK", "optc": "HeLa", "optd": "BTK", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}